<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>If Colorful</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/</link><description>Recent content on If Colorful</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ifcolorful.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Redesigning my Website</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/website-v2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/website-v2/</guid><description>Redesigning my Website When I launched my personal website back in January, I used a publicly available Hugo theme and tweaked some parts of it without comfortably knowing exactly how Hugo worked, how the theme was structured, and how the CSS was written. However, this month I gave web design another try when my friend asked me to help redesign his static website that was built using Pelican, another static site generator that&amp;rsquo;s powered by Python instead of Go.</description></item><item><title>Kaleidoscope</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/kaleidoscope/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/kaleidoscope/</guid><description>Inspiration Earlier this year, I did a series of mini, incy, teeny tiny projects called Random Sketches with the goal of learning Canvas. In my opinion, Canvas has more differences than similarities from D3.js, but a hybrid of the two works very well when it comes to visualizing many distinct data points. Wtih this knowledge of Canvas, I could now do projects that focus purely on graphics without thinking about how to fit it to the data.</description></item><item><title>Holst - The Planets</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/gustav-holst/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/gustav-holst/</guid><description>Inspiration I started practicing oboe again. Thank you TwoSet Violin 🎻🎻 for making me go practice. While getting back into classical music and trying to be more cultured, I wanted to reexplore music data as my next data project. I had once analyzed Spotify data last year in my previous work where I colored musical flowers based on their chroma feature, so I wanted to take another shot at visualizing music with the same interesting data but in a different way.</description></item><item><title>Random Sketches</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/random-sketches/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/random-sketches/</guid><description>Why work with no data? In my typical data visualization process, I would form the question, collect and clean the data, explore data trends and anomalies, and then think of ways to communicate data effectively and creatively. It&amp;rsquo;s a long process with many dead ends, especially when wanting to tell something not told before. If I wanted to get better at the coding aspect, then I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting enough practice&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Chinese New Year</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/chinese-new-year-greetings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/chinese-new-year-greetings/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the Season Again! This vibrant Sugarfina ad in my inbox caught my eye, and I was so excited to find out they were promoting for Chinese New Year. Their packaging sparks so much joy! 🥲 Kudos to their design team. Their red and yellow color palette inspired me to create my own Chinese New Year design.
Finding the 成語 Data and Design The toughest part of this project was finding available data related to Chinese New Year.</description></item><item><title>Building my First Website</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/website-v1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/website-v1/</guid><description>My 2021 New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution was to have an online portfolio that would help me stay organized and honestly just have the right to flex with my friends.
This post is unlike my other content that have more visual creativity, but I think my first experience with website hosting deserves a write-up. Without having any knowledge prior, I spent about 40 hours getting this to work. So painful. :( But now that I actually understand this, I could probably manage this under 2 hours next time.</description></item><item><title>College Football</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/college-football/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/college-football/</guid><description>What is the Circle of Suck? I drew the &amp;ldquo;Circle of Suck&amp;rdquo; for NCAA college football conferences for 2019 as a joke on my boyfriend&amp;rsquo;s obsession with USC football. The Circle of Suck is complete when all the schools in a conference loses to another school (school A &amp;lt; school B &amp;lt; school C &amp;hellip; &amp;lt; school A). I usually see people scramble to post these jokes on Twitter, Reddit, and Facebook.</description></item><item><title>Spotify Flowers</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/spotify-flowers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/spotify-flowers/</guid><description>Overview I worked on this project in 2 phases: Proof of Concept and Productionizing. Phase 1 includes creating the standalone visual, which took roughly 4 weeks. Phase 2 includes using Python flask to build the application, generalizing layout of the flower visual, and deploying, which took roughly another 4 weeks. I started Phase 2 6 months after completing Phase 1 because I learned about deploying data applications from the Data Engineering team at work.</description></item><item><title>U.S. Elections</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/us-elections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/us-elections/</guid><description>From November 3 to November 6, 2020 It felt like the whole world was watching the live updates on the U.S. Election. I started seeing so many impressive data visualizations sprout up that I wanted to contribute with my own infographic.
I got my data source from the MIT Election Lab, which provided presidential election data from 1976 to 2016, and Britannica, which provided the latest table of U.S. electoral votes by state.</description></item><item><title>Fortune 100</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/fortune-100/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/fortune-100/</guid><description>Data Collection with Selenium I usually use BeautifulSoup in Python to web-scrape data based on the page&amp;rsquo;s HTML code. However, the Fortune 100 has some sneaky thing that doesn&amp;rsquo;t render the HTML code unless you click a button to see more, making BeautifulSoup useless by itself. I used this blog post to learn how to use Selenium because someone else faced this issue before me (and solved this problem before me).</description></item><item><title>Yelp</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/yelp-culver-city/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/yelp-culver-city/</guid><description>Data Collection I used the business search endpoint from Yelp&amp;rsquo;s API to collect data on any type of business in Culver City, CA, which is where I was working at the time. I saved my data in .csv form because I was most familiar with this format based on my experience using python pandas. In my opinion, saving as a JSON allows for more flexibility in D3 but is not always necessary.</description></item><item><title>Theme Park Operations</title><link>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/theme-park-operations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ifcolorful.com/projects/theme-park-operations/</guid><description>My first internship at Disney encouraged me to use my graphic design ability Every intern is required to create a report-out presentation that highlights a few of their projects. My Workforce Management department consisted heavily of cast members who were working in the parks and got promoted to work as a scheduler, analyst, and eventually manager. When doing projects based on a lot of mathematical formulas, it was really easy for many people to get lost.</description></item></channel></rss>